

# **Executive Summary**

Archaeologist with 9 years of experience conducting desk based research as well as fieldwork on historical archaeological sites such as Carthage and Empúries.

Currently leveraging my greatest skills in analysis, research, observation and conservation to excel in my work on commercial heritage consultancy projects, as well as guiding heritage planning and promoting policies on conservation.

## **Hard Skills**



# Languages

Arabic (Limited working)

French (Full professional)

Spanish (Full professional)

English (Native or bilingual)

## **Achievements**

+ Wooly Mammoth Preservation + One of my most recent significant achievements was preserving a Wooly Mammoth skeleton while working with Wessex Archaeology.

# **Out of Office**



In my free time I like trekking and hiking. This activity enables me to relieve stress, keep fit, and enjoy time in nature.

# SAMANTHA INGRAM Archaeologist

☑ samanthaingram3@gmail.com

+44 077 0007 0004

M Bristol, England, UK

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### HERITAGE CONSULTANT

Wessex Archaeology, Bristol, UK

07/2015 - Present

Wessex Archaeology is a leading provider of heritage services to a range of sectors and clients across the UK.I was working on commercial heritage consultancy projects, undertaking desk based research, heritage planning guidance and conservation policy; assessing impacts to the setting and significance of heritage assets.

#### JUNIOR ARCHAEOLOGIST

10/2014 - 07/2015

## Archaeological Site of Carthage, Tunisia

After being in Tunisia's famoust archaeological site for a trainee in 2009 I had the great honor of being able to manage a discrete area of work within restoration of new Thermas discovered in 2014.

# ENGLISH SPEAKING GUIDE

06/2013 - 10/2014

MAC Empúries, Spain

I spent a year as one of the English guides at Empúries archaeological site located in the mediterranean north coast of Spain. Empúries is the only archaeological site in the Iberian Peninsula where remains a place where the Greek-Emporion colony enclave- with the remains of a Roman city founded in the early 1st century BC on the structures of a Roman military camp installed during the previous century.

#### **ARCHAEOLOGY TRAINEE**

07/2009 - 09/2009

Archaeological Site of Carthage, Tunisia

The Traineeship I assisted consisted in field work helping the District of Tunis Archaeological staff on the restoration and maintenance work at the Archaeological Site of Carthage, protected by Unesco Heritage Program for Historic Monuments since 1985.

### **EDUCATION**

ARCHAEOLOGY
UCL Institute of Archaeology
09/2012 - 05/2013

ANTHROPOLOGY MRES University College London 09/2007 - 08/2011

GCE ADVANCED LEVEL
North Bridge House Senior Canonbury
09/2000 - 06/2007

Scan the QR code to view my online resume with more information about my soft skills, achievements, references & more.

https://cvonline.me/example3

